# Siddhi Thakur

Buffalo, NY | 7162924314 | siddhithakur56@gmail.com | github.com/siddhithakur | linkedin.com/in/siddhi-m-thakur

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Dedicated and skilled software developer with 3 years of experience in software development, specializing in data analysis, machine learning, and back-end scripting. Seeking to contribute my technical expertise and problem-solving skills to a dynamic development team.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming languages : Python, Java, C, C++, JavaScript, HTML

Packages/ Libraries : Numpy, Pandas, CV2, Beautiful Soup, Scikit-learn, NLTK, Spacy, Tensorflow

Database : MySQL, Neo4j, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Apache Solr

Operating System : Windows, Linux, MacOS

Tools/IDE/ Frameworks : Git, Docker, Pycharm, Postman, Selenium, VScode, Apache Spark, Kibana, Flask, Pytest, Django

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Developer | London Stock Exchange Group | Buffalo, New York

Apr 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality software enhancements within project timelines.
- Identified and rectified software defects by enhancing the Pearl Script and refining the HTML templates to accommodate new fields and formats, resulting in a 40% reduction in effort for modelers.
- Restructured the Database table, Loan Tags, and implemented a C++ Script to model Non-QM deals for efficient data collation and storage, resulting in a 30 MB data saving per deal across 1000s of NQM deals.
- Enhanced Python and C++ code in Loan Loader app to integrate One Deal Update scripts, streamlining data updates, saving valuable time for the Collateral team.

#### Senior Software Engineer | Infosys Text Analytics Platform | Infosys, Pune, India

Apr 2020 - May 2021

- NLP-driven microservices-based solution that supports document and FAQ search. Built data ETL in Spring Boot and prepared custom parsing logic in Python to extract data from around 4000 documents (pdf, excel, doc, docx, pptx) and data from other formats like XML, JSON.
- Developed backend API in Flask to ingest the extracted data received via Kafka to Elasticsearch index and RESTful services with Swagger for
- Search API in Java, for keyword and semantic search based on cosine similarity. Used Git for version control and deployment monitoring.
- Utilized agile methodology to design, develop, and test along with software and tools like REST APIs, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Docker, GitLab.
- Researched and reduced the response time for semantic search by 50% by Fine-tuning BERT Sentence transformer model.

#### Software Engineer | Cvent - Pfizer | Infosys, Pune, India

May 2018 - Mar 2020

- Designed and demonstrated an automation workflow of Manual tasks using Java and Selenium for a Salesforce-based meetings management tool saving around 10 person-hours per week. Received Insta Award for this initiative.
- Presented team stats reports using Pivot tables. Quality Checks and Data Analysis using SQL.
- Led a Team of 6 as a System Admin and promoted agile practices to manage client tickets and requests effectively.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Decentralized Blockchain-based Food Selling application**

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022

- Implemented a Smart Contract to buy and sell food items using Solidity, Remix and Truffle development suite and integrated the ERC20 token to enable the exchange of tokens on purchase.
- Connected the smart contract to HTML, JavaScript-based User Interface using Web3 and hosted on Heroku.

#### **Stock Market Management System**

Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

- Developed a full-stack web application using Spring Boot REST API and React for UI.
- Built a PostgreSQL database for the stock market data mapped to user data in the system.

## Web Application to demonstrate RAFT Consensus Algorithm - Advertising Platform

Feb 2022 - May 2022

- Created a Distributed Systems Application to buy and sell products using Flask serving as REST API with React as the frontend.
- Implemented Multi-node leader election and log replication to achieve data consistency across 5 different nodes by processing client requests using Docker. Used Object-Oriented, Socket binding and multithreading concepts for development.

## Dissecting Twitter data to analyze government & public attitudes toward Covid and vaccines

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

- Hosted an end-to-end search system on an AWS cloud EC2 instance. Scraped and indexed around 200K multi-lingual tweets in Solr.
- Analyzed data to gauge public sentiments and topic-modeling of tweets with interactive plots in Angular.

#### **EDUCATION**

University at Buffalo, The State University of New York

Aug 2021 - Feb 2023

Master's of Computer Science

GPA - 3.7 /4.0

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

Jul 2013 - Aug 2017

Bachelor's of Technology in Computer Engineering

GPA - 8.15/10